RG 004:009, Bethel Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Bethel Probate Court records
1859-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Bethel District)
26.75 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1859-1976; Probate files, 1859-1929.
RG004_009
1931-001 and 1985-046
Historical Note
Bethel, Fairfield County, Town established in May 1855 Parent Town: Danbury
The Bethel Probate District was constituted July 4, 1859, from the Danbury Probate District. The Bethel Probate District merged with the Newtown, Redding, and Ridgefield Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Northern Fairfield County Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethel, Newtown, Redding and Ridgefield.
Town of Bethel, Probate District chronology:
May 1855 - July 3, 1859, Danbury District
July 4, 1859 - January 4, 2011, Bethel District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Northern Fairfield County District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1859-1976. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 37. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1859-1929. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1859-1929 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 37. One volume of bonds is unnumbered.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1931-001 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Bethel
Places:
Bethel (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1929 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15.
Accession 1987-046, Record books, 1859-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1, 3, 5, 6, 8, 9, 11, 13, 1859-1931; probate files, 1859-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1931-001 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 4, 1931 and span the years 1859-1929.
Container List
- Record books, 1859-1976; 19.5 cubic feet (39 volumes); 1985-046
  - Records, 1859 July - 1975 May, 1886 May 1 (Volume 1)
  - Decrees, 1873 January - 1885 May (Volume 2)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1873 January - 1898 June (Volume 3)
  - Decrees, 1885 August - 1897 December (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1885 August - 1894 January (Box 5)
  - Records, 1893 July - 1902 July (Volume 6)
  - Decrees, 1896 June - 1907 February (Box 7)
  - Records, 1900 July - 1907 October (Volume 8)
  - Applications and returns, 1903 July - 1931 October (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1905 October - 1913 March (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1907 September - 1913 June (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1912 October - 1921 October (Volume 12)
  - Decrees, 1913 June - 1918 January (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1913 June - 1918 January (Box 13)
  - Records, 1917 December - 1922 January (Volume 14)
  - Bonds, 1918 May - 1942 June (Volume 15)
  - Decrees, 1920 May - 1927 June (Volume 16)
  - Decrees, 1926 September - 1935 January (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1922 January - 1925 January (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1924 December - 1931 April (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1931 May - 1937 January (Volume 20)
  - Applications, 1931 October - 1952 January (Volume 21)
  - Decrees, 1932 August - 1935 May (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1937 January - 1941 January (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1943 March - 1947 February (Volume 24)
  - Bonds, 1942 September - 1963 March (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1947 January - 1950 June (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1950 July - 1954 February (Volume 27)
  - Applications, 1952 March - 1969 September (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1954 January - 1957 December (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1957 August - 1960 February (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1960 February - 1962 November (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1962 November - 1966 January (Volume 32)
  - Applications, 1969 October - 1976 May (Volume 33)
  - Bonds, 1963 January - 1976 July (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1966 January - 1969 February (Box 35)
  - Records, 1969 February - 1972 September (Box 36)
  - Records, 1972 September - 1975 December (Volume 37)
    Contains pages 1-600
  - Records, 1975 December - 1976 June (Volume 37)
    Contains pages 601-1200
  - Bonds, 1881 October - 1918 May (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1859-1929; 7.25 cubic feet; 1931-001
  - Abbott - Baird, H. (Drawer 1)
  - Baird, J. - Beckett (Drawer 2)
  - Beebe - Britovich (Drawer 3)
  - Brooke - Cole (Drawer 4)
  - Coley - Dibble (Drawer 5)
  - Dikeman - Edmonds (Drawer 6)
  - Edwards - Ferry, K. (Drawer 7)
  - Ferry, L. - Fry (Drawer 8)
  - Gage - Grumman (Drawer 9)
  - Hawes - Hoyt, F. (Drawer 10)
  - Hoyt, G. - Judd, E. (Drawer 11)
  - Judd, F. - Kinner (Drawer 12)
  - Knapp - Lyon, I. (Drawer 13)
  - Lyon, J. - Mills (Drawer 14)
  - Moffat - Osborn, L. (Drawer 15)
  - Osborn, M. - Ritzman (Drawer 16)
  - Roach - Sherwood (Drawer 17)
  - Short - Starr, C. (Drawer 18)
  - Starr, D. - Taylor, A. (Drawer 19)
  - Taylor, B. - Trowbridge (Drawer 20)
  - Turner - Whitney (Drawer 21)
  - Wiehman - Z, Miscellaneous (Drawer 22)
- Inventory Control Book, 1859-1929; T003073
  Index of the probate files in accession 1931-001
  Also known as the Godard Digest